petsafe.net 2019-07-01

# Privacy Policy

General  
Data Usage  
Inquiries and Complaints  
Children's Privacy  
Acquisitions and Other Reorganisations  
Security  
Legal Requests  
California Privacy Rights (“Shine the Light” Law)  
Personal Data of EU and Swiss Residents  
Controllers and Processors  
3rd Party Processing containing Personal Data of EU and Swiss Residents  
Access, Correction and Removal of Personal Data  
Opting Out  
Independent Dispute Resolution  
Links to Third-Party Sites / Products / Services  
Cookies Policy  
3rd Party Cookie Usage  
Do Not Track Requests  
Helpful Tips on Managing Cookies

**This document was last updated May 8th, 2018.**

##  General

The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you how Radio Systems Corporation, its brands including, but not limited to PetSafe®, SportDOG®, Invisible Fence®, Premier Pet®, and Free Spirit® brand, and its affiliates (collectively referred to as "RSC", “we”, “us”, “our(s)”), gathers, uses and shares information about you. We appreciate your trust that we will do so cautiously.

This Privacy Policy includes but is not limited to RSC “Website”, “Websites”, “WebPage”, “WebPages”, “Web Page”, “Web Pages”, “Page”, “Pages”, “Site”, “Sites”, “Service” “Services”, “Mobile Apps”, “Mobile Applications”, “Smart Products”.

You may contact us at Attn: Risk Management, Radio Systems Corporation, 10427 PetSafe Way, Knoxville, TN 37932 or you may send an e-mail to [privacy-dept@radiosystemscorporation.com](mailto:privacy-dept@radiosystemscorporation.com).

Inquires made by email may be responded to by email, the sender is consenting to return replies by email unless it is specified to return communications through another method.

This Privacy and Cookie Policy may be changed over time. Such changes shall be effective immediately upon the posting of the modified Privacy and Cookie Policy. Users of the Website are advised to regularly read the Privacy and Cookie Policy for possible changes

##  Data Usage

RSC’s primary goal in collecting personal information from you is to provide you with a smooth, efficient and customized experience and to assist with purchasing, ordering, and support.  This allows us to provide services and features that most likely meet your needs and to improve your experience.

RSC only processes personal data that a user voluntarily consents to provide to RSC. This information may include your name, date of birth, gender, address, IP addresses, product details, equipment or device, GPS coordinates or location data, additional usage and device data may be collected through the use of "Smart Products” and "Mobile Apps".

We may require you to create an “Account” or "Smart Product Account" prior to using services, purchasing items through the website, registering your product, registering or accessing warranty information, registering for any contest, or other content submission.

We ask that you provide us with certain information during the registration process. While you are not required to do so, if you are unable or unwilling to do so, you will not be able to complete the registration process, and therefore you will not be able to access and use certain information, material and services.

Additionally, we will use personal data and communication preferences to determine the best method to communicate with you in regard to your account or services.

Personal data may be used in investigations related to violations of policy, terms and service agreements, acceptable usage, and unauthorized or attempted unauthorized access. Legal and regulatory reporting including where disclosure is necessary to identify, contact, or bring legal action regarding injury or interference with the rights and property of RSC.

##  Inquiries and Complaints

You may contact us at Attn: Risk Management, Radio Systems Corporation, 10427 PetSafe Way, Knoxville, TN 37932 or you may send an e-mail to [privacy-dept@radiosystemscorporation.com](mailto:privacy-dept@radiosystemscorporation.com).

Inquires made by email may be responded to by email, the sender is consenting to return replies by email unless it is specified to return communications through another method.

##  Children's Privacy

We take children's privacy seriously. This Website is not directed to children. We do not seek to collect personal information about children through our Website. We ask that minors (under the age of 18) do not submit any personal information to us. If we learn that someone under the age of 18 has submitted information to us through any part of our Website, we delete the information as soon as we discover it and do not use it for any purpose, nor do we disclose it to third parties. Since we do not seek to collect any personal information about children, and we delete information collected inadvertently as soon as we discover that a child has submitted it, we typically retain no information about children that can be reviewed or deleted. If a parent requests review or deletion of information about their child before we have discovered and removed the information, we will honor that request.

##  Acquisitions and Other Reorganizations

Information collected pursuant to this Privacy Policy, including Protected Personal Information, may be disclosed to one or more third parties in connection with any change of ownership or control in RSC’s business (whether by merger, sale, or otherwise), or any other reorganization or joint venture, or assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of our business, assets or stock (including in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceeding), and any such information may be used by such third party in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Equally, information collected pursuant to this Privacy Policy, including Personal Information, may be disclosed to one or more third parties in connection with any acquisition or merger carried out by RSC of such third parties.

As we continue to develop our business, we might sell or buy stores, subsidiaries, or business units. In such transactions, customer information generally is one of the transferred business assets but remains subject to the terms in any pre-existing Privacy Policy. In the unlikely event that RSC or substantially all its assets are acquired, customer information will be one of the transferred assets.

##  Security

Perfect security does not exist on the internet and we cannot guarantee anyone complete security. Your privacy is import to us and we use industry standard practices to protect your privacy, we cannot promise, and you should not expect, that your personally identifiable information or private communications will remain private and would never be disclosed in a manner that is inconsistent with this Privacy Policy. You understand that third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications, and other users may abuse or misuse your personal information that they collected from this Website. Please note that emails, messages sent via your web browser, and other similar means of communication with other users, are not encrypted. We strongly advise you not to communicate any confidential or sensitive information through these means. Please also be aware that we may use third-party cloud service providers that provide hosting, data storage and other services pursuant to standard terms and conditions that may be nonnegotiable; these service providers have informed us or the public that they apply security measures they consider adequate for the protection of information within their system, or they have a general reputation for applying such measures. However, we will not be liable (to the fullest extent permitted by law) for any damages that may result from the misuse of any information, including Personal Information, by these companies.

##  Legal Requests

Radio Systems cooperates with law enforcement and other third parties to enforce laws, intellectual property and other rights.

In response to a verified request relating to a criminal investigation or other alleged improper or illegal activity, we may disclose information relevant to the investigation including, but not limited to, name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, IP address, user history and complaints.

Legal and regulatory reporting where disclosure is necessary to identify, contact, or bring legal action regarding injury or safety interference with the rights and property of RSC.

Without limiting the above, we will not otherwise disclose your personal information to law enforcement or other third parties, except as specifically outlined in this Privacy Policy, without a subpoena, court order or substantially similar legal procedure, except when we believe in good faith that the disclosure of this information is necessary to prevent imminent physical harm or financial loss or to report suspected illegal activity. In addition, we may transfer information about you if we are acquired by or merge with another company.

This includes but is not limited to the following:

RSC is committed to cooperating with EU data protection authorities (DPAs) and the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (FDIC) and comply with the advice given by such authorities regarding human resources data transferred from the EU and Switzerland in the context of the employment relationship.

RSC is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC)

You may contact us at Attn: Risk Management, Radio Systems Corporation, 10427 PetSafe Way, Knoxville, TN 37932 or you may send an e-mail to [privacy-dept@radiosystemscorporation.com](mailto:privacy-dept@radiosystemscorporation.com)

##  California Privacy Rights (“Shine the Light” Law)

California residents who provide personal information in obtaining products or services for personal, family, or household use are entitled to request and obtain from us once a calendar year information about the customer information we shared, if any, with other businesses for their own direct marketing use. If applicable, this information would include the categories of customer information and the names and addresses of those businesses with which we shared customer information for the immediately prior calendar year (e.g., requests made in 2016 will receive information regarding 2015 sharing activities).

##  Personal Data of EU and Swiss Residents

The following section pertains to users which are in the European Union and Switzerland. RSC will transfer certain data to RSC in the United States. RSC will comply with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union member countries and Switzerland to the United States.

RSC has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity, and Purpose Limitation, Access, Recourse, Enforcement and Liability. If there is any conflict between the policies in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

In the context of an onward transfer of data to a third party, a Privacy Shield organization has responsibility for the processing of personal information it receives under the Privacy Shield and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. RSC shall remain liable under the Principles if its agent processes such personal information in a manner inconsistent with the Principles, unless RSC proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

Residents of the European Economic Area and Switzerland have a right of access to their data. If you wish RSC to access and edit such data on your behalf, identity verification may be required to authorize transactions.

European Economic Area and Switzerland residents also have a right, if their personal data is inaccurate, of rectification, erasure or blocking of such inaccurate personal data. You may alternatively request RSC to rectify, erase or block the data by sending a certified letter, with a copy of your passport or national identity card (for identity verification purposes), to the above address with the exact nature of the requested action.

##  Controllers and Processors

RSC operates under the following lawful basis: Consent, Contract, Legal Obligation, and Processing not requiring identification. More specific information about these lawful bases can be found at <https://gdpr-info.eu/art-6-gdpr/>

**For North America:**

  * Attn: Risk Management, Radio Systems Corporation, 10427 PetSafe Way, Knoxville, TN 37932 (“RSC”) is the controller of all personal data collected.

**International operations (specifically EU):**

  * Luzern Technology Solutions Ltd (“Luzern”) is the controller of all personal data collected:
  * Luzern Technology Solutions Ltd. Blanchardstown Business & Technology Park, Snugborough Road, Blanchardstown, Dublin 15, Ireland. Co. Reg. #361832, Dublin, Ireland.
  * Website: <http://www.luzern.co/privacy-policy/>
  * Email: [info@luzern.co](mailto:info@luzern.co)

##  3rd Party Processing containing Personal Data of EU and Swiss Residents

RSC may utilize 3rd parties to assist with certain functions of the business. This may include hosting of RSC systems and / or processing activities which may include personal data processing. 3rd parties are inspected for and are expected to comply with all applicable laws governing Protected Personal Data including but not limited to General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), applicable Data Protection Acts, and Privacy Shield regulations including but not limited to the transport of data.

For international (Specifically EU) please contact Luzern:

  * Luzern Technology Solutions Ltd. Blanchardstown Business & Technology Park, Snugborough Road, Blanchardstown, Dublin 15, Ireland. Co. Reg. #361832, Dublin, Ireland.
  * Website: <http://www.luzern.co/privacy-policy/>
  * Email: [info@luzern.co](mailto:info@luzern.co)

##  Access, Correction and Removal of Personal Data

You can request RSC to provide access to the personal data it has collected about you at any time. You can also request RSC to correct or to delete such personal data. Please send an email to [privacy-dept@radiosystemscorporation.com](mailto:privacy-dept@radiosystemscorporation.com) in case you have any questions concerning your personal data.

This Privacy and Cookie Policy may be changed over time. Such changes shall be effective immediately upon the posting of the modified Privacy and Cookie Policy. Users of the Website are advised to regularly read the Privacy and Cookie Policy for possible changes.

For international (Specifically EU) please contact Luzern:

  * Luzern Technology Solutions Ltd. Blanchardstown Business & Technology Park, Snugborough Road, Blanchardstown, Dublin 15, Ireland. Co. Reg. #361832, Dublin, Ireland.
  * Website: <http://www.luzern.co/privacy-policy/>
  * Email: [info@luzern.co](mailto:info@luzern.co)

##  Opting Out

If you no longer want to receive promotional materials from us based upon your Personal Information, going forward, you may opt out of receiving such marketing related messages by sending an email to [privacy-dept@radiosystemscorporation.com](mailto:privacy-dept@radiosystemscorporation.com). Please note that we may still send other messages to you, such as administrative messages. We will try to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable.

##  Independent Dispute Resolution

In compliance with the US-EU and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles, RSC commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact RSC at:

Attn: Risk Management, Radio Systems Corporation, 10427 PetSafe Way, Knoxville, TN 37932, or by emailing [privacy-dept@radiosystemscorporation.com](mailto:privacy-dept@radiosystemscorporation.com).

There may be a possibility, under certain limited conditions, for EU and Swiss individuals to invoke binding arbitration before the Privacy Shield Panel.

RSC has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles to the JAMS. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit <https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield> for more information and to file a complaint. The services of JAMS are provided at no cost to you.

There may be a possibility, under certain limited conditions, for EU and Swiss individuals to invoke binding arbitration before the Privacy Shield Panel.

##  Links to Third-Party Sites / Products / Services

This Website may contain links to other sites.  When you click on such links, you may leave our Site. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our Site. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected on this Website. “Smart Devices” may contain features to integrate or share data with 3rd parties, if sharing data with a 3rd party please refer to that company’s privacy policy.

WE ARE NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR THE INFORMATION COLLECTION, USE, DISCLOSURE OR OTHER PRIVACY PRACTICES OF ANY THIRD PARTY, INCLUDING OUR AFFILIATES, THIRD-PARTY SERVICE PROVIDERS, ANY EMPLOYERS (INCLUDING ANY EMPLOYER THAT PROVIDES A COMPANY PAGE), ANY THIRD-PARTY SOCIAL MEDIA PLATFORM, ANY THIRD PARTY MAKING AVAILABLE THE DEVICES OR OPERATING SYSTEMS FOR WHICH THE SITE IS AVAILABLE, AND ANY THIRD PARTY OPERATING ANY WEBSITE TO WHICH THE SITE CONTAINS A LINK. YOU MAY HAVE RIGHTS DIRECTLY ENFORCEABLE AGAINST THESE THIRD PARTIES, SO YOU SHOULD CONSIDER THEIR PRIVACY POLICIES TO LEARN MORE.

##  Cookies Policy

Cookie Preferences

This policy helps to explain the occasions when and why cookies may be sent to visitors to the Website (referred to in this policy as “we”, “us” or “our”). “Cookies” are text-only pieces of information that a website transfers to an individual’s hard drive or other website-browsing equipment for record-keeping purposes.

While using our Website we may store and access these cookies on your device. Accepting these cookies may be required for proper functionality of the website. While you have the right to prevent cookies from being created and stored we cannot guarantee how our site will perform for you.

Cookies allow the Website to remember essential information that will make your use of the site more convenient. A cookie will typically contain the name of the domain from which the cookie has come, the “lifetime” of the cookie, and a randomly generated unique number or other value. Certain cookies will be used on the Site regardless of whether you are logged in to your account or not.

Like most websites, we use cookies for a variety of purposes, primarily to improve your online experience, for analytics and for marketing, and marketplace functionality. We may specifically we use Cookies on the Website for the following purposes:

**Analytical Purposes:**

We use cookies to analyze user activity to enable us to improve the website usage experience. Examples of the information we may collect and analyze include:

  * Your Device’s unique device ID
  * IP and/or MAC addresses
  * Pixel Tags
  * The domain from which you access the internet
  * The kind of browser or Device you use
  * Your Device’s operating system
  * The address of the internet site, banner or email from which you selected or entered a link that brought you to this Website
  * The number of links you click within this Website
  * The state or country from which you accessed this Website
  * The date and time of your visit and how long you spent visiting the Website
  * The pages you viewed on the Website
  * Purchase history
  * Interactions within the Website or App you are using

We can use such analysis to gain insights about how to improve the functionality and user experience of the Website.

**Required and Marketing Cookies:**

On this site, we have required cookies and marketing cookies. Marketing cookies collect and store personal data from our clients to help us provide you with a better experience as you use our site. If you do not want us to collect that data and store it in those marketing cookies, you can utilize our cookie preferences widget to enable or disable the use of marketing cookies.

Required cookies are necessary to the core functionality of our e-commerce platform and as such cannot be turned off with the preferences widget. Required cookies do not collect or store any personal data from our clients as they are only used for core functionality.

**Your Preferences:**

We may use Cookies to store certain user preferences on our Website. For example, we may store the recent searches you have performed in a Cookie so that we can allow you to easily repeat those searches when you return to our Website.

Session Cookies are temporary cookies that remain in the cookie file of your browser until you leave the Website.

Persistent Cookies remain in the cookie file of your browser for much longer (though how long will depend on the lifetime of the specific cookie). When we use session cookies to track the total number of visitors to our Website, this is done on an anonymous aggregate basis (as cookies do not in themselves carry any personal data). We may also employ cookies so that we remember your computer when it is used to return to the Website to help customize your RSC web experience.

We may associate personal information with a cookie file in those instances. Use the options in your web browser if you do not wish to receive a cookie or if you wish to set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie. You can easily delete any cookies that have been installed in the cookie folder of your browser.

Furthermore, you can prevent Google's collection and use of data (cookies and IP address) by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available under <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en-GB#> . You may disable the use of Google Analytics by using the link disable Google Analytics. This link creates an opt-out cookie which prevents the further processing of your data.

To block Google Analytics cookies specifically, you can install the [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/) provided by Google.

##  3rd Party Cookie Usage

Communication Cookies allow cookies of third party social networks (e.g. Facebook, YouTube, Twitter, LinkedIn). This enables a user to share content of the Website on social networks. These third parties may use cookies, but their use of cookies will not be governed by this Cookie Policy.

Performance cookies help us to understand the behavior of our visitors and the usage of the Website. This allows us to continuously improve the Website to provide you the best website experience.

These cookies are also used to help us understand what interests our users, and measure how effective our advertising is.

Some cookies are managed by third parties, and you may refer to the third parties' own website privacy notifications for further information.

We use Google Analytics cookies to obtain an overall view of visitor habits and visitor volumes, and to help improve the overall experience on our website.

We use Google Analytics, a third-party web analysis service provided by Google Inc., which uses "performance cookies" and "targeting cookies" to analyze how you use the Website. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the Website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States.

However, this website uses Google Analytics with the expansion '_anonymizeIp()' which means that Google will truncate/anonymize the last octet of the IP address for Member States of the European Union.

You can find more information on the _anonymizeIp() expansion from Google Analytics Help Page, specifically <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2763052?hl=en>

On behalf of us, Google will use the information collected for the purpose of evaluating your use of our Website, compiling reports on website activity and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage to us. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google.

**Get Site Control Information:**  
This site utilizes the GetSiteControl to set marketing cookies and collect personal data from our clients in order to provide surveys, promos, and feedback widgets to our clients. This service is completely optional, and you can refuse to use utilize this service by opting out of our marketing cookies in the cookie preferences widget.

Get Site Control collects personal data in the form of IP address, location, browser information, device information, and any data you provide in our feedback and survey forms. You can request that this data be removed by making an email request to [privacy-dept@radiosystemscorporation.com](mailto:privacy-dept@radiosystemscorporation.com).

##  Do Not Track Requests

We do not respond to the browser “Do Not Track” (DNT) signal if enabled by the user in their web browser. When we set or read cookies on non-RSC sites that have integrated our features, we do so. We do not share any information about your use of RSC with those third parties. When third parties that we have integrated into RSC sites (as described in the RSC Cookie Policy) set or read their own third-party cookies, they may or may not respond to the DNT signal.

##  Helpful Tips on Managing Cookies

If you disable all cookies, you may not be able to take advantage of all the features of this website. Consult your mobile device documentation for information on how to disable cookies.

Once you have given us your agreement to the use of cookies, we shall store a cookie on your computer or device to remember this for next time. If you wish to withdraw your agreement at any time, you will need to delete our cookies using your internet browser settings. You should do this through the browser settings for each browser you use. Please be aware that some of our services will not function if your browser does not accept cookies. However, you can allow cookies from specific websites by making them "trusted websites" in your internet browser. The following links may assist you in managing your cookies settings, or you can use the 'Help' option in your internet browser for more details.

Internet Explorer:  
<https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies>

Mozilla Firefox:  
<http://support.mozilla.com/en-US/kb/Cookies>

Google Chrome:  
[http://www.google.com/support/chrome/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=95647](http://www.google.com/support/chrome/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=95647)

Safari:  
<http://support.apple.com/kb/PH5042>

Opera:  
<http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/privacy/>

To block Google Analytics cookies specifically, you can install the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on provided by Google.

_Please check the browser’s cookie settings support pages to confirm the most up-to-date instructions._

Google Chrome

  * Click the settings icon on the browser toolbar (three stacked lines)
  * Select ‘Settings’
  * Click ‘Show advanced settings’
  * In the “Privacy” section, click the ‘Content settings’ button
  * To enable cookies: In the “Cookies” section, pick ‘Allow local data to be set’. This will enable both first-party and third-party cookies. To allow only first-party cookies, pick ‘Block third-party cookies and site data’
  * To disable cookies: In the “Cookies” section, pick ‘Block sites from setting any data’
  * Note there are various levels of cookie enablement and disablement in Chrome. For more information on other cookie settings offered in Chrome, refer to the following page from Google: <https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647>

Mozilla Firefox

  * Click the menu button (three stacked lines) and choose ‘Preferences’
  * Select the Privacy panel
  * Set ‘Firefox will:’ to ‘Use custom settings for history’
  * To enable cookies: Check ‘Accept cookies from sites’
  * To disable cookies: Uncheck ‘Accept cookies from sites’
  * Note there are various levels of cookie enablement and disablement in Firefox. For more information, refer to the following page from Mozilla: <https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences>

Safari on OSX

  * Click on ‘Safari’ at the menu bar and select the ‘Preferences’ option
  * Click on ‘Privacy’
  * To enable cookies: In the ‘Cookies and website data:’ section, click ‘Always Allow’ or ‘Allow from websites I visit’ or ‘Allow from current website only’ depending on your preference
  * To disable cookies: In the “Cookies and website data:” section, click ‘Always Block’
  * Note there are various levels of cookie enablement and disablement in Safari. For more information on other cookie settings offered in Safari, refer to the following page from Apple: <https://support.apple.com/kb/PH19214>

Opera

  * From the main menu, select ‘Settings’ (or ‘Preferences’, when using OS X)
  * Click ‘Advanced’
  * Under “Cookies”, select an option for handling cookies
  * To enable cookies: Check ‘Accept’ or ‘Accept only from the sites I visit’ depending on your preference
  * To disable cookies: Check ‘Never accept cookies’
  * Note there are various levels of cookie enablement and disablement in Opera. For more information on other cookie settings offered in Opera, refer to the following page from Opera Software: <http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/privacy/>

Microsoft Internet Explorer 6.0, 7.0, 8.0, 9.0, 10.0

  * Click on ‘Tools’ at the top of your browser window and select ‘Internet Options’
  * In the options window navigate to the ‘Privacy’ tab
  * To enable cookies: Set the slider to ‘Medium’ or below
  * To disable cookies: Move the slider to the top to block all cookies
  * Note there are various levels of cookie enablement and disablement in Explorer. For more information on other cookie settings offered in Internet Explorer, refer to the following page from Microsoft: <https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies>

Microsoft Internet Explorer 11 for Windows 10

  * Click on ‘Tools’ at the top of your browser window and select ‘Internet Options’
  * In the options window navigate to the ‘Privacy’ tab
  * To enable cookies: Choose ‘Allow’ or ‘Be prompted for first and third party cookies,’ depending on your preferences
  * To disable cookies: Choose ‘Block’
  * Note there are various levels of cookie enablement and disablement in Explorer. For more information on other cookie settings offered in Internet Explorer, refer to the following page from Microsoft: <https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies>

Microsoft Edge

  * Click on ‘More’ and choose ‘Settings’
  * Under “Advanced settings”, select ‘View advanced Settings’
  * Under “Privacy and services – Cookies”, choose the option you want.
  * ‘Block all cookies’ blocks all cookies that websites try to save to your computer. ‘Block only third party cookies’ blocks third party cookies, which are saved by external web services, such as ads embedded on webpages you have navigated to.
  * Note there are various levels of cookie enablement and disablement in Edge. For more information on other cookie settings offered in Microsoft Edge, refer to the following page from Microsoft: <https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/12454/windows-10-microsoft-edge-privacy-faq>
